[SOUND] So
那么
often we want to visualize multiple variables simultaneously.
我们经常会想要同时 可视化多个变量
And so we generate stacked graphs that can display several variables
于是 我们创造了堆叠图 它能显示若干变量
changing along the same dimension.
沿相同维度的变化。
For a bar chart, we may want to look at more than just a single quantitative
对于一个柱状图 我们想看的也许 不限于仅量度在一个维度内
dependent variable measured across an independent variable dimension.
随自变量而变化的因变量
One way of doing this is with a stacked bar chart.
做到这一点的一种方法 是使用一个堆叠的柱状图
In this case we can have two or more dependent variables plotted.
在这种情况下 我们可以 绘制两个或更多的因变量
In this case, the blue bars are representing one dependent variable and
在这个例子中 蓝色的柱状部分 代表一个因变量
the red bars are representing a second dependent variable.
红色的柱状部分 代表第二个因变量
And so we're using q to represent different nominal value, basically
于是我们用 q 表示不同的面值 本质上来说
the second dependent variable is different than the first dependent variable.
第二个因变量不同于 第一个因变量
And then the total amount of the contribution of both variables
那么 两个变量所贡献的总数量
is represented by the height of the top of these stacked bars.
别表现为这些堆叠柱状 顶部的高度
And the relative proportion is being represented by
而相对比例被表示为
the proportion of the bar being one color versus another color.
一种颜色柱体和 另一种颜色柱体的比例
And if we want to emphasize that relative proportion.
并且 如果我们想强调 这样的相对关系
We can have the bars stacked to 100% and
我们可以把柱体堆叠到 100%
just plot the percentage of the contribution of one variable versus
仅用不同颜色的柱体画出 一个变量与
the other variable as the difference in the colors of the bars.
另一个变量相比各自所占的百分比
This kind of relative contribution is also represented in a pie chart but
这种类型的相对比较 也可用饼状图来表示
in a pie chart you're representing the contribution based on angle and
但在饼状图中 用的是角度
a little bit by area than on position and length.
少数是用面积 而不是用位置和长度
Here in a pie chart the relative proportion of the blue category
这里 在饼状图中 表现为蓝色的类别 桔色类别
versus the orange category versus the green category versus the yellow category
绿色类别 及黄色类别 的相对比例
is being represented by the angle as the angle's sum to 360 degrees.
通过角度的大小来区别 而所有角度的总和为360度
It's also proportional to the area represented by each of these four regions.
其比例也是和四个区域间 面积的比例是一样的
That indication can be degraded somewhat if you try to
如果你试图用一个三维的饼状图来表示
show a pie chart in three dimensions.
这一表征方式会稍微有所减弱
And that's because in three dimensions we are still perceiving
这是因为在三维中我们依然
a three dimensional scene as a two dimensional image.
在将一个三维场景 看作一个二维图像
And the visual cues we're using include foreshortening and perspective.
并且 我们使用的视觉线索 包括透视收缩和透视变换
And those cues can get in the way of our ability to perceive a region, say in
这些线索会妨碍我们 感知一个区域的能力
the foreground, as being larger or smaller than a region in the background because of
例如近景中的一个区域比远景中的一个区域 显得更大或者更小 因为
our expectation that perspective is going to make regions in the foreground larger.
在我们的透视中 习惯认为近景中的区域更大
Or at least appear larger and regions in the background appear smaller,
或者至少看起来更大 而远景中的区域看起来更小
even if it's just a orthographic non-perspective projection.
甚至它只是一个 正射的非透视投影
So, it's best not to use three dimensions for pie charts and, in fact,
所以 做好不要使用三维 饼状图 且事实上
it's better just to use a stacked bar chart instead of a pie chart.
最好只使用堆叠 柱状图而不用饼状图
In this case, each one of these bars can represent a separate pie chart
在这个例子中 这些柱体的每一个 能够表现一个单独的饼状图
because it's representing the separate relative contribution to the whole of
应为它表现了 随着某个自变量变化的
multiple dependent variables, as they vary across some independent variable.
多个因变量在整体中各自所占的比例
Also, stacking order matters.
并且 堆叠顺序是有重要的
I've got the same data plotted in the left and in the right.
我在左右两边 画的是同样的数据
In the left, I've plotted the blue variable first.
在左边 我先画的是蓝色的变量
And then I've stacked the red variable on top of that.
然后将红色变量 堆叠到它上面
On the right side, I've plugged the red variable first and
在右边 我先画了红色变量
I've stacked the blue variable on top of that.
然后将蓝色变量堆叠到其上面
On the right it's easy to see that the red variable isn't changing
在右边非常容易看出 沿着横轴方向
across the horizontal axis.
红色变量没有变化
On the left, you can still see that the red variable isn't changing, but
在左侧，你仍能看到 红色变量没有在变化
you have to see that because the lengths aren't changing.
但你必须看出这是 因为它们的长度没有变
Whereas on the right, the actual positions aren't changing.
相对来说 在右侧 实际位置没有变化
Which further verifies that position is a stronger indicator than the length of
这进而证实 对于绘制两个几何和空间上 特殊显示的元素而言
the actual data values in terms of mapping two geometric and
相比于实际数据值的长度
spacial display elements.
位置是一个更强的指标
You can avoid that stacking order problem by using diverging stacked bar charts if
你可以使用外散型堆叠柱状图 来避免堆叠顺序问题
you have the red variable creating bars growing upwards, and
如果用红色变量 产生向上伸展的柱体
the blue variable creating bars growing downward.
并用蓝色变量 产生向下伸展的柱体
But that stops working when you have three or more variables.
但是 当你有三个或更多变量 的时候 这种方法就不起作用了
Another way to avoid having one variable dominate the other in stacking order
另一个防止一个变量在堆叠顺序 上比其它变量占优的方法
is to stack them and then re-center the bar across the horizontal axis.
是将它们堆叠之后 再将柱体沿横轴中心对齐
So instead of growing up from the horizontal axis
即 柱体仅以横轴为中线对齐
the bar is just centered at the horizontal axis.
而不是从横轴向上伸展
And this give us the same displacement on the top and
这样在柱状图的顶部和底部 这给我们
the bottom of the bar chart, but it helps us to pay more
相同的偏移 但有助于我们更加
attention to the areas of the elements instead of their actual position.
关注于元素的面积 而不是它们的实际位置
It's much better if you have continuously changing horizontal and vertical
如果纵横方向都是连续的变量 那么绘制堆叠的线状图
axis variables to use stacked line graphs, then stacked bar charts.
比绘制堆叠的柱状图效果会好很多
If we can connect their data values by lines instead of having them
如果我们可以用线来连接数据值 而不是用
discrete bars, then it's easier to see when areas are changing
离散的柱体 那么会更容易看到
versus areas are remaining constant as they move across even
面积随轴线在变化 而不是保持不变
though they're displaced by the variance of other variables.
即使它们因其它变量 的变化而偏离了原始位置
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community